Sometimes, you might not be able to
有时候 可能因为没有多个小组
run a true experiment to test your hypotheses due to not having
或者无法做到随机分配小组
multiple groups or not being able to control random assignment to groups.
导致无法运行实验来检测假设
This will require you to consider alternative study designs.
这时候就需要考虑替代性研究设计了
We can think of the types of study as lying on a spectrum
研究类型按照这个图谱分布
based on the amount of control we have over the variables in play.
该图谱基于我们对所涉变量的控制程度
On the end with a high level of control,
在最右端 控制程度最高
we have an experiment.
我们可以运行实验
On the complete opposite side,
在另一端
where we have no control is the observational study.
我们完全无法控制 这时候就需要采用观察性研究了
A classic example of this is on the risks posed by smoking.
一个典型示例是研究吸烟的风险
The hypothesis is that smoking tobacco
假设吸烟能够增加
increases the likelihood of developing diseases like lung cancer.
肺癌等疾病的患病率
Due to the risks of subjects actually developing a disease,
由于存在可能会导致受试者患病的风险
it would be unreasonable not to mention unethical for us to
所以为了运行实验并测试假设而让人们吸烟
make people smoke in order to run an experiment for testing our hypothesis.
不仅不合理 而且不道德
Instead, we need to rely on collecting data passively making connections
我们需要被动地收集数据
between smoking rates and disease incidences based on groups or matched individuals.
并根据小组或相符的受试者判断吸烟和疾病之间的关系
Establishing causality is very difficult
对于观察性研究来说
or perhaps even impossible with an observational study,
确定因果关系很难 甚至不可行
but if the feature of interest is something that
但是 如果研究人员
the researcher cannot or should not manipulate,
不能或不应控制感兴趣的因素
then an observational design might be the only path to take.
那么观察性设计可能是唯一可行的方法
You can also have studies that fall in the middle
有些研究还可以介于
of observational studies and experiments.
观察性研究和实验之间
If your study applies some,
如果研究能够采用真实实验所需的
but not all of the controls required of a true experiment,
部分而非全部控制措施
then you have a quasi-experiment instead.
那么这就是一项准实验
One example of this is when a video game company rolls out
举个例子 假设有个游戏公司想要推出
a patch to modify character and item attributes.
会修改角色和装备属性的补丁程序
This may then have an effect on character and item popularity.
该补丁程序可能会影响到角色和装备的受欢迎程度
Since everyone is affected in the same way,
因为所有人受影响的程度都一样
this is a quasi-experiment.
所以这是一项准实验
We only have one group to track and there's no control group.
我们只能跟踪一组数据 没有对照组
In our analysis, we can only compare
在分析过程中
the games ecosystem from before the patch and from after the patch.
我们只能对比发布补丁程序前后的游戏生态系统
If we do see changes then there is the possibility for
如果出现变化 也有可能是因为
other factors to have caused these changes not just the patch itself.
其他因素导致了这些变化 不仅仅只是因为补丁程序本身
For this scenario, we wouldn't want to run the patch as a true experiment.
对于这种情形 我们不能以真实实验的形式运行补丁程序
If we randomly split users between pre-patch and post-patch groups,
如果随机地将用户分配到发布补丁程序前后的小组
this fracturing could cause friction among the user base.
则可能会导致用户群受到影响
Friends could end up in different versions and unable to play with one another.
好友可能会分配到不同的版本 无法组队玩游戏
Even if we made a beta patch available for players to test out changes,
即使推出测试版补丁程序 请玩家测试更改
this still wouldn't be a true experiment since
也不能算作真实实验
the players would be self-selecting themselves into the test.
因为玩家可能会选择参加测试
It's quite possible that the players that will want to
很有可能想要尝试新补丁程序的玩家
try out a new patch are different from the players in
与普通群体的玩家不一样
the general population limiting
导致我们无法判断
our ability to make conclusions about the effect of the patch.
补丁程序的效果如何